A Guide to the William Hewitt Phillips Papers, 1918-2008
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
- Series II. 2010 Donation
  - Subseries I. Writings and Lectures, 1936-2000
    - NACA Advance Confidential Reports, 1942, [reprints] (Box-folder 35-4)
      - Stalling Characteristics of the Supermarine Spitfire va Airplane
      - Measurements of the Flying Qualities of a Supermarine Spitfire va Airplane
    - NACA Advance Restricted Reports, 1942-1944, [reprints] (Box-folder 35-5-6)
      - Effect of Spring and Gravity Moments in the Control System of the Longitudinal Stability of the Brewster XSBA-1 Airplane
      - Flight Tests of Various Tail Modifications on the Brewster XSBA-1 Airplane: I - Measurements of Flying Qualities with Original Tail Surfaces
      - Stability of a Body Stabilized by Fins and Suspended from an Airplane
      - Application of Spring Tabs to Elevator Controls
    - NACA Memorandum Reports, 1942-1944, [reprints] (Box-folder 35-7-8)
      - Measurements of the Flying Qualities of A Hawker Hurricane Airplane
      - Flight Tests of Various Tail Modifications on the Brewster XSBA-1 Airplane: II - Measurements of Flying Qualities with Tail Configuration Number Two
      - Measurements of Flying Qualities of a Curtiss SB2C-1 Airplane
    - NACA Reports, 1944-1949 (Box-folder 35-9)
      - Application of Spring Tabs to Elevator Controls
      - Appreciation and Prediction of Flying Qualities
    - NACA Research Memoranda, 1950-1958 (Box-folder 36-1-2)
      - Low-speed Tests of a Model Simulating the Phenomenon of Control-Surface Buzz
      - Ability of Pilots to Control Simulated Short-Period Yawing Oscillations
      - Investigation of Effect of Reduction of Valve Friction in a Power Control System by Use of a Vibrator
      - Review and Investigation of Unsatisfactory Control Characteristics Involving Instability of Pilot-Airplane Combination and Methods for Predicting These Difficulties from Ground Tests
      - Theoretical Investigation of Some Discontinuous Yaw Dampers
      - Analysis of an Automatic Control to Prevent Rolling Divergence
      - Analysis of Effects of Interceptor Roll Performance and Maneuverability on Success of Collision-course Attacks
    - NACA Restricted Bulletins, 1944-1945, [reprints] (Box-folder 36-3)
      - Effect of Lateral Shift of Center of Gravity
      - The Use of Geared Spring Tabs for Elevator Control
    - NACA Technical Notes, 1946-1957 (Box-folder 36-4-7)
      - An Investigation of Additional Requirements for Satisfactory Elevator Control Characteristics
      - Effect of Steady Rolling on Longitudinal and Directional Stability
      - Appreciation and Prediction of Flying Qualities
      - Theoretical Analysis of Oscillations of a Towed Cable
      - Theoretical Analysis of Some Simple Types of Acceleration Restrictors
      - Flight Investigation of the Effectiveness fo an Automatic Aileron Trim Control Device for Personal Airplanes
      - Investigation by the Transonic-bump Method of a 35 [degree] Sweptback Semispan Model Equipped with a Flap Operated by a Series of Servovanes Located Ahead of and Geared to the Flap
      - Loads Implications of Gust-Alleviation Systems
    - NASA Technical Memoranda, 1960-1990 (Box-folder 36-8)
      - Research on Blunt-faced Entry Configuratinos at Angles of Attack between 60 [degrees] and 90 [degrees]
      - Comparison of Effects of Unsteady Lift and Spanwise Averaging in Flight through Turbulence
      - Altitude Response of Several Airplanes During Landing Approach
      - Effect of Structural Flexibility on the Design of Vibration-isolating Mounts for Aircraft Engines
      - Determination of the Pressure Drag of Airfoils by Integration of Surface Pressures
    - NASA Technical Note, 1973 (Box-folder 36-9)
      - Study of a Control System to Alleviate Aircraft Response to Horizontal and Vertical Gusts
    - NASA Technical Paper, 1978-1980 (Box-folder 36-10)
      - Ground Distance Covered During Airborne Horizontal Deceleration of an Airplane
      - Some Design Considerations for Solar-powered Aircraft
    - NASA Technical Report, 1960 (Box-folder 36-11)
      - The Lateral Response of Airplanes to Random Atmospheric Turbulence
    - Outline of lecture material available, 1975 (Box-folder 36-12)
    - Penetration into the Wind, n.d. (Box-folder 36-13)
    - Power Boost, Artificial Feel, and Acceleration Restrictions, n.d. (Box-folder 36-14)
    - Power Control Systems and Control Feel Devices for Satisfactory Airplane Handling Qualities, 1954 (Box-folder 36-15)
    - Presentation to Dr. Low, 1970 (Box-folder 36-16)
    - Propellor Design Program, 1978-1986, n.d. (Box-folder 36-17)
    - Propulsive Effects Due to Flight Through Turbulence, 1975, n.d. (Box-folder 36-18)
    - Propulsive Effects of Radiator and Exhaust Ducting, 1941 (Box-folder 36-19)
    - Propulsive Efficiency of Tail-mounted Turbofan Engines, 1968 (Box-folder 37-1)
    - Recent Studies of Stability and Control Characteristics of Fighter Airplanes and Their Relation to Tactical Requirements, 1952 (Box-folder 37-2)
    - Recent Trends in U. S. Aeronautics and Research Technology, 2000 (Box-folder 37-3)
    - Recollections of Langley in the Forties (Langley Colloquium Series),1990 (Box-folder 37-4)
    - Recollections of Langley in the Forties [videocassette], 1990 (Box-folder 37-5)
    - Recollections of Langley Memorial Aero Lab in the Forties, 1992 (Box-folder 37-6)
    - A Review and Analysis of the Applications of Gust-alleviation Systems, 1972 (Box-folder 37-7)
    - Review of Docking Studies at the Langley Research Center, 1963 (Box-folder 37-8)
    - Rubber-powered Radio-control Models, 1968 (Box-folder 37-9)
    - Samuel Pierpont Langley - Astronomer and Aeronaut, [1992?] (Box-folder 37-10)
    - Selected Projects in Langley Research Center Guidance and Control Research, 1977 (Box-folder 37-11)
    - Similarities and Contrasts Between Ship Design and Aircraft Design, 1955 (Box-folder 37-12)
    - Simple Determination of Reynolds Number, 1998 (Box-folder 37-13)
    - Simulation Research at Langley Research Center, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 37-14)
    - Stability and Control (comments on) [audiocassette], n.d. (Box-folder 37-15)
    - Stability and Control Problems at Transonic and Supersonic Speeds and Problems of Aiming and Sighting Guns at Transonic Speeds, n.d. (Box-folder 37-16)
    - Stable Platforms and Inertial Navigation Systems, 1959 (Box-folder 37-17)
    - Studies of Friction Drag and Pressure Drag of Airfoils Using the Eppler Program, 1988, n.d. (Box-folder 38-1-2)
    - A Study of Means for Limiting the Maximum Normal Acceleration of Airplanes n.d. (Box-folder 38-3)
    - Symbols and Nomenclature for Model Aeronautics, 1994, n.d. (Box-folder 38-4)
    - Theoretical Study of Means to Increase the Smoothness of Flight Through Rough Air, n.d. (Box-folder 38-5)
    - Unsteady Lift lecture, 1966 (Box-folder 38-6)
    - Use of Models to Solve Problems of Full-size Aircraft, [1999?] (Box-folder 38-7)
    - What's a Joule, Newton?, n.d. (Box-folder 38-8)
    - Where Does the Lift Come From? Where Does It Go?, n.d. (Box-folder 38-9)
    - Wind-Tunnel Study of Canard Surfaces on the Shuttle Orbiter, 1985 (Box-folder 38-10)
  - Subseries II. Subject Files, 1927-2004
    - Aberdeen Ballistic Research Laboratories visit, 1952 (Box-folder 38-11)
    - Aerospace / aviation memorabilia, 1976-1981, n.d. (Box-folder 38-12)
    - Air Scoop (Langley Memorial Aeronautical Laboratory newsletter), 1944-1962 (Box-folder 38-13)
    - Airplane drawings, 1963, n.d. (Box-folder 38-14)
    - American Institute of Aeronautics and Astronautics, 1967-1995 (Box-folder 38-15)
    - Apollo XI 20th anniversary, 1989 (Box-folder 38-16)
    - Award programs and correspondence, 1962-1981 (Box-folder 38-17)
    - Beech Bonanza, 1953-1987 (Box-folder 39-1)
    - Defense aircraft model plans, 1942 (Box-folder 39-2)
    - Design for Aeromodellers, 1953, [photocopy] (Box-folder 39-3)
    - Event programs and invitations, 1963-1989 (Box-folder 39-4)
    - Fairchild 22 Handbook of Instructions, n.d. (Box-folder 39-5)
    - Experimental Aircraft Association convention, 1982 (Box-folder 39-6)
    - Free fall technique, 1947-1995, n.d. (Box-folder 39-7)
    - Gliders - world record, 1992-1994, n.d. (Box-folder 39-8)
    - Handbook of the National Aircraft Collection, 1932 (Box-folder 39-9)
    - Hang gliders, n.d. (Box-folder 39-10)
    - Hang gliders - model tests [16 mm film], n.d. (Box-folder 39-11)
    - Hang gliders, 1974-1976, n.d. (Box-folder 39-12)
    - Hirsch, Rene - GH-80, 1975, n.d. (Box-folder 39-13)
    - Jex, Henry R., 1991-1998 (Box-folder 39-14)
    - Joshi, Suresh M., 1988, n.d. (Box-folder 39-15)
    - Journey in Aeronautical Research - correspondence, 1999 (Box-folder 39-16)
    - Kites, 1991, n.d. (Box-folder 39-17)
    - Kraft, Christopher C., 1965, n.d. (Box-folder 40-1)
    - LMAL Bulletin, 1942-1944 (Box-folder 40-2)
    - Langley 75th anniversary, 1992 (Box-folder 40-3)
    - Langley Aerospace Mechanics Division personnel list, 1962 (Box-folder 40-4)
    - Langley Colloquium: Design, Construction and Flight Testing of the Spirit of St. Louis, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 40-5)
    - Langley Researcher, Dec 30 1966 (Box-folder 40-6)
    - Langley Stability and Control Section personnel records, 1944-1967, n.d. (Box-folder 40-7-9)
    - Larrabee, E. Eugene, 1963-1995 (Box-folder 49-10)
    - Lindbergh, Charles, 1927-2001, n.d. (Box-folder 40-11)
    - A Longitudinal Control Feel System for In-flight Research on Response Feel - by Faber and Crane, 1961 (Box-folder 40-12)
    - Lunar Orbit and Landing Approach Simulator, 1964-1967, n.d. (Box-folder 40-13)
    - Lunar orbit rendezvous plan, 1961-1966, n.d. (Box-folder 40-14)
    - Man Will Never Fly Memorial Society, 2001, n.d. (Box-folder 40-15)
    - Maxim, Hiram, 1985-1998, n.d., [2 folders] (Box-folder 41-1)
    - Measurement of 3-dimensional shapes, 1983, n.d. (Box-folder 41-2)
    - Model aircraft, 1963-1993, n.d. (Box-folder 41-3)
    - Model championships, 1988 (Box-folder 41-4)
    - Modifications and Tests of Curtiss P-40 Airplane for Improvement of Ground Handling Characteristics - R. R. Gilruth and M. N. Gough, 1940 (Box-folder 41-5)
    - National Academy of Engineering election, 1991 (Box-folder 41-6)
    - National Advisory Committee for Aeronautics booklets, 1943-1944, n.d. (Box-folder 41-7)
      - Work for Victory
      - NACA - LMAL and You
      - A Career in Aeronautical Research
    - Neural networks, 1991-1993, n.d. (Box-folder 41-8)
    - Norton, Frederick H., 1966-1981 (Box-folder 41-9)
    - Orbiting telescope, 1964-1965 (Box-folder 41-10)
    - Ornithopters, 1981-1996, n.d. (Box-folder 41-11)
    - Patent 2,821,352: Servo vane control for aircraft, 1954-1958 (Box-folder 41-12)
    - Patent 3,104,079: Variable-geometry winged reentry vehicle, 1959-1989, n.d. (Box-folder 41-13)
    - Patent 3,386,686: Station keeping of a gravity-gradient stabilized satellite, 1965-1968 (Box-folder 42-1)
    - Patent 4,281,384: Rim inertial measuring system, 1981 (Box-folder 42-2)
    - Patent 4,415,133: Solar-powered aircraft, 1978-1983, n.d. (Box-folder 42-3)
    - Performance and Dynamics of Aerospace Vehicles, 1971 (Box-folder 42-4)
    - Propeller design program - foreign requests, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 42-5)
    - Propeller designs, 1979, n.d. (Box-folder 42-6)
    - Propeller dynamics, 1994 (Box-folder 42-7)
    - Requirements for Satisfactory Flying Qualities - by R. R. Gilruth, 1941 (Box-folder 42-8)
    - SBD-5 Aileron failure - Flight 21 [16 mm film], n.d. (Box-folder 42-9)
    - Sand dunes - Nag's Head, North Carolina, 1974-1996, n.d. (Box-folder 42-10)
    - Shuttle landing dynamics, 1977-1979, n.d. (Box-folder 43-1)
    - Shuttle trainer aircraft, 1973-1976 (Box-folder 43-2)
    - Solar sail, 1977 (Box-folder 43-3)
    - Space News Roundup, 1962-1963 (Box-folder 43-4)
    - Steam-powered helicopter (1842 design), 1984-1986, n.d. (Box-folder 43-5)
    - Supersonic glider with folding canard, 1972, n.d. (Box-folder 43-6)
    - The Systems-Dynamics Research Airplane - by S. A. Sjoberg, 1958 (Box-folder 43-7)
    - Thermic sniffler theory and calibration, 1971, n.d. (Box-folder 43-8)
    - Thick suction airfoils, 1991, n.d. (Box-folder 43-9)
    - Thompson, Floyd L., 1937-1988 (Box-folder 43-10)
    - Trimmed drag - Milton D. McLaughlin, 1977-1982 (Box-folder 43-11)
    - Unsteady lift, n.d. (Box-folder 43-12)
    - Vibration-isolating mounts for radial engines, 1984-1987 (Box-folder 43-13)
    - Virginia Air and Space Center, 1988-1997, n.d. (Box-folder 43-14)
    - Weiss, Herbert K., 1939-1962, n.d. (Box-folder 43-15)
    - White Pelican Project: world's largest paper airplane, 1987-1992, n.d., [2 folders] (Box-folder 43-16)
    - Wind tunnel research, 1948-1967 (Box-folder 43-17)
    - Windmill boat, 1965 (Box-folder 43-18)
    - Wing Tips (NACA Lewis Flight Propulsion Laboratory newsletter), 1945-1948 (Box-folder 43-19)
    - Wright Brothers, 1962-2004, n.d., [3 folders] (Box-folder 44-1)
    - Young Men in Aeronautics: A Twenty-year Progress Report of the Lawrence B. Sperry Award, 1957, [2 items] (Box-folder 44-2)
    - Unidentified 16 mm film, n.d. (Box-folder 44-3)
  - Subseries III. Correpondence Files, 1943-2008
    - Abzug, Malcolm, 1994-2004 (Box-folder 44-4)
    - Alaback, G. James, 1992-1995 (Box-folder 44-5)
    - Bacon, Jack, 1990 (Box-folder 44-6)
    - Baker, Paul S., 1988-1991 (Box-folder 44-7)
    - Bauer, Andrew B., 1993-1994 (Box-folder 44-8)
    - Baxter, Dick, 1994 (Box-folder 44-9)
    - Beatty, J. Roger, 1976 (Box-folder 45-1)
    - Bennett, Jim, 1980 (Box-folder 45-2)
    - Bennett, Leon, 1985 (Box-folder 45-3)
    - Bradley, Jim, 1986 (Box-folder 45-4)
    - Brand, Rolf, 1981 (Box-folder 45-5)
    - Breznikar, Radoslav, 1987, n.d. (Box-folder 45-6)
    - Brill, Yvonne (NAE), 1995 (Box-folder 45-7)
    - Brocklehurst, Alan, 1985-1986, n.d. (Box-folder 45-8)
    - Carmichael, Bruce, 1988-1995, n.d. (Box-folder 45-9)
    - Chana, William F., 1987-1988 (Box-folder 45-10)
    - Chernoff, Max, 1983-1986 (Box-folder 45-11)
    - Cole, Hank, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 45-12)
    - Colson, Stanley V., 1994 (Box-folder 45-13)
    - Cone, Don, 1965 (Box-folder 45-14)
    - Crowley, R. T., 1979 (Box-folder 45-15)
    - Deshaye, Pat, 1985 (Box-folder 45-16)
    - Dodds, Robert P., 1978-1993 (Box-folder 45-17)
    - Douglas, Debbie, 1999-2002 (Box-folder 45-18)
    - Edwards, John C., 1963 (Box-folder 45-19)
    - Eggleston, Jack, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 45-20)
    - Eppler, Richard, 1983 (Box-folder 45-21)
    - Fife, Bob, 1991 (Box-folder 45-22)
    - Fogel, Larry, 1976 (Box-folder 45-23)
    - Foshag, William, 1996 (Box-folder 45-24)
    - Gale, Ferdi, 1976-1981 (Box-folder 45-25)
    - Ganser, Ronald, 1987 (Box-folder 45-26)
    - Gill, John D., 1980 (Box-folder 45-27)
    - Gilruth, Robert R., n.d. (Box-folder 45-28)
    - Girsberger, Rolf, 1979-1982 (Box-folder 45-29)
    - Goldsberg, Carl, 1980 (Box-folder 45-30)
    - Goldschmied, Fabio R., 1990 (Box-folder 45-31)
    - Good, Walter A., 1989-1996 (Box-folder 45-32)
    - Graham, Dunstan, 1949 (Box-folder 45-33)
    - Gremmer, Hans, 1986 (Box-folder 46-34)
    - Gue, Frank, 1979-1986 (Box-folder 45-35)
    - Hannan, Bill, 1983-1994 (Box-folder 45-36)
    - Harlan, Raymond B., 1979 (Box-folder 45-37)
    - Hatschek, R. L., 1988 (Box-folder 45-38)
    - Hill, Maynard, 1984-2003, n.d. (Box-folder 45-39)
    - Hirsch, Rene, 1979-1995, n.d. (Box-folder 45-40)
    - Italiano, A. J., 1981-1985 (Box-folder 45-41)
    - Jarrett, Philip, 1985-1988 (Box-folder 45-42)
    - Jones, David W., 1967-1970 (Box-folder 45-43)
    - Kelley, Herbert L., 1988-1992 (Box-folder 45-44)
    - Keshishian, Harry, n.d. (Box-folder 45-46)
    - Kiker, John W., 2002 (Box-folder 45-47)
    - Kraft, Christopher C. Jr., 1978-1980 (Box-folder 45-48)
    - Kuhrt, Wesley A., n.d. (Box-folder 45-49)
    - Lardinois, Ryan, 1991-1993, n.d. (Box-folder 46-1)
    - Larrabee, Eugene, 1949-1997 (Box-folder 46-2)
    - Lee, Edward R., 1980-1987 (Box-folder 46-3)
    - Lin, Charissa, 1994 (Box-folder 46-4)
    - Linstrum, Dave, 1986 (Box-folder 46-5)
    - Mann, Peter M., 1993 (Box-folder 46-6)
    - Mattill, John I., 1988 (Box-folder 46-7)
    - McBride, J. Wallace, 1981-1993 (Box-folder 46-8)
    - McCombs, William F.,1993-1995 (Box-folder 46-9)
    - McCutcheon, Charles, 1989-1995, n.d. (Box-folder 46-10)
    - McRuer, Duane T., 1995 (Box-folder 46-11)
    - Meuser, Robert B., 1975-2000, n.d. (Box-folder 46-12)
    - Michael, William H. Jr., 1982 (Box-folder 46-13)
    - Michel, Peter, 1988 (Box-folder 46-14)
    - Mitrovich, M., 1980 (Box-folder 46-15)
    - Monson, Donald, 1979 (Box-folder 46-16)
    - Mooney, Walt, 1988 (Box-folder 46-17)
    - Morris, Gilbert, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 46-18)
    - Moulton, R. G., 1976 (Box-folder 46-19)
    - Nicks, Oran W., 1974-1992 (Box-folder 46-20)
    - Ober, Shatswell, 1983 (Box-folder 46-21)
    - Ogden, Thomas G., 1994 (Box-folder 46-22)
    - Opdycke, Leonard E., 1988-2004, n.d. (Box-folder 46-23)
    - Oringer, Sanford, 1968-1996 (Box-folder 46-24)
    - Orrell, John, 1978 (Box-folder 46-25)
    - Padfield, Gareth, 2002-2004 (Box-folder 46-26)
    - Patrick, Tom J., 1985-1987 (Box-folder 46-27)
    - Pearce, George E. Jr., 1988-1994 (Box-folder 46-28)
    - Penton, D. N., 1987-1988 (Box-folder 46-29)
    - Perkins, Courtland, 1969 (Box-folder 46-30)
    - Persh, Jerome, 1978 (Box-folder 46-31)
    - Pieromarchi, Bruno, 1950-1955 (Box-folder 46-32)
    - Pond, Bertram, 1989-1995, n.d. (Box-folder 46-33)
    - Radcliffe, Lynn, 1975-2004, n.d. (Box-folder 47-1)
    - Rash, Fred H., 1987-1988, n.d. (Box-folder 47-2)
    - Richmond, James, 1987 (Box-folder 47-3)
    - Rodensky, Erving, 1995 (Box-folder 47-4)
    - Ryanski, Edmund G., 1994-1995 (Box-folder 47-5)
    - Selig, Michael, 1983-1984, n.d. (Box-folder 47-6)
    - Sherlock, Stuart, 1996-2008, n.d. (Box-folder 47-7)
    - Simons, Martin, 1983-1987 (Box-folder 47-8)
    - Smith, A. M. O., 1994 (Box-folder 47-9)
    - Steinmeyer, Peter, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 47-10)
    - Strack, K. J., 1984 (Box-folder 47-11)
    - Teiser, Eugene S., 1976 (Box-folder 47-12)
    - Tenny, Bud, 1964-1969 (Box-folder 47-13)
    - Thomas, Don, 1989 (Box-folder 47-14)
    - Turner, Bill, 1993 (Box-folder 47-15)
    - Vogelsang, William, 1988 (Box-folder 47-16)
    - von Flotow, Andreas, 1988 (Box-folder 47-17)
    - Voorhees, John, 1988 (Box-folder 47-18)
    - Walker, John L., 1985 (Box-folder 47-19)
    - Wantzenriether, Jean, 1983 (Box-folder 47-20)
    - Ward, Lou, 1990-1991, n.d. (Box-folder 47-21)
    - Warner, Bill, 1994 (Box-folder 47-22)
    - Weinreich, Chris, 1993-1997, n.d. (Box-folder 47-23)
    - Weiss, Herbert K., 1943-2003, n.d., [7 folders] (Box-folder 47-24-48-1)
    - Westbrook, Charles, 1995 (Box-folder 48-2)
    - Whipple, Ray, 1993, n.d. (Box-folder 48-3)
    - Wilson, Douglass, 1977-1986 (Box-folder 48-4)
    - Withington, Betsy and Bob, 1994 (Box-folder 48-5)
    - Wolkovitch, Julian, 1984 (Box-folder 48-6)
    - Xenakis, George, 1988 (Box-folder 48-7)
    - Youngren, Harold, 1994 (Box-folder 48-8)
    - Zaic, Frank, 1983-2005, n.d. (Box-folder 48-9)
    - Unidentified correspondents, 1950-1988, n.d. (Box-folder 48-10)
  - Subseries IV. Photographs, 1932-1990
    - Phillips studio portraits, [1963?]-1986, n.d. (Box-folder 48-11)
    - Phillips snapshots, ca. 1932-ca. 1970 (Box-folder 49-1)
    - President's Award for Distinguished Federal Civilian Service color transparencies, 1979 (Box-folder 49-2)
    - Award presentations, 1944-1982, n.d. (Box-folder 49-3)
    - Viola Phillips touring Johnson Space Center, n.d. (Box-folder 49-4)
    - Unidentified banquet / reception, [1976?] (Box-folder 49-5)
    - Unidentified banquet, n.d. (Box-folder 49-6)
    - Meetings, 1970, n.d. (Box-folder 49-7)
    - Receptions, 1977-1990, n.d. (Box-folder 49-8)
    - Virginia H. Knauer (special assistant to the president for consumer affairs) Langley visit, 1976 (Box-folder 49-9)
    - [NACA test pilots?] (Pilgrim, Whitten, C. Mathews, Raskley, D'Orazio, Reeder), n.d. (Box-folder 49-10)
    - Unidentified crew with biplane, ca. 1930 (Box-folder 49-11)
    - Langley Research Center color transparencies, n.d. (Box-folder 49-12)
  - Subseries V. Personal Life, Education, and Career, 1918-2008
    - Biographical materials and ephemera, 1918-1989, n.d. (Box-folder 49-13)
    - Newsclippings, 1944-1992, n.d. (Box-folder 49-14)
    - Diaries, 1929-[2007?] (Box-folder 50-1-52-2)
    - Travel diary - England, 1966 (Box-folder 52-3)
    - Appointment / address book, 1978 (Box-folder 52-4)
    - Belmont High School, 1928-1939, n.d. (Box-folder 52-5)
    - Massachusetts Institute of Technology, 1935-1942, n.d., [4 folders] (Box-folder 52-6-53-1)
    - Technique (MIT annual), 1939 (Box-folder 53-2)
    - Massachusetts Institute of Technology, 1970-1999, n.d. (Box-folder 53-3)
    - Trip to North Carolina State University, 1988 (Box-folder 54-1)
    - Trip to Oklahoma City and San Antonio, 1989 (Box-folder 54-2)
    - Trip to San Diego, 1988 (Box-folder 54-3)
    - Trip to Syracuse and Binghampton, 1989 (Box-folder 54-4)
    - Retirement social scrapbook, 1979, [2 folders] (Box-folder 54-5)
    - Retirement congratulatory notes, 1979-2008 (Box-folder 54-6)
    - Retirement scrapbook, 1979 (Box-folder 54-7)
    - Academy of Model Aeronautics Brainbuster Club / gold member plaque, n.d. (Box-folder 54-8)
    - Allan H. Taylor Memorial Award (Hampton Roads Section, AIAA) plaque, 1996 (Box-folder 54-9)
    - AIAA Dryden Lecture in Research medal, n.d. (Box-folder 54-10)
    - American Institute of Aeronautics and Astronautics medal, n.d. (Box-folder 54-11)
    - American Astronautical Society Fellowship plaque, 1985 (Box-folder 55-1)
    - Experimental Aircraft Association Special Recognition Award plaque, 1982 (Box-folder 55-2)
    - Langley Research Center Outstanding Volunteer Service Group Award plaque, 1981 (Box-folder 55-3)
    - Langley Research Center Special Achievement Award plaque, 1981 (Box-folder 55-4)
    - NASA service medals, 1979-1987, n.d., [3 items] (Box-folder 55-5)
    - National Free Flight Society plaque, [1987?] (Box-folder 56-1)
    - Peninsula Engineer of the Year Award (Engineers' Club of the Virginia Peninsula), 1996 (Box-folder 56-2)
    - President's Distinguished Federal Civilian Service Medal, n.d. (Box-folder 56-3)
    - Patent 4,281,384 (Rim inertial measuring system) plaque, [1981?] (Box-folder 56-4)
    - Patent 4,415,133 (Solar-powered aircraft) plaque, [1983?] (Box-folder 56-5)
    - Certificate awards, 1929-2006 (Box-folder 56-6-57-1)
    - American Institute of Aeronautics and Astronautics 15th Technical Symposium plaque, 1989 (Box-folder 57-2)
    - NACA plaque, 1979 (Box-folder 57-3)
    - Plaque bearing control position transmitter used in flight control testing, 1950 (Box-folder 57-4)
  - Oversize Materials
    - Photograph: attendees of the NACA 75th anniversary reception, 1990 (Oversize 1)
    - Photograph: 10th reunion, MIT class of 1939, 1949 (Oversize 1)
    - Belmont High School diploma, 1932 (Oversize 1)
    - Special Award - Approach and Landing Test Program, 1978 (Oversize 1)
    - President's Award for Distinguished Federal Civilian Service, 1979 (Oversize 1)